Tanishq Kumar

599 3rd Street, Unit 103 San Francisco, CA, USA 415-860-6595 tanishq@careerfear.org

18 year old on a gap year, freelancing as a full-stack software engineer while running an award-winning international nonprofit. Most interested in the intersection of physics/CS. Lived in Kentucky, Ohio, New York, Delhi, Abu Dhabi, London, San Francisco, and, next year, Boston. Speak English, Hindi, French fluently. Value technical strength of peer group above all; very flexible with salary/work hours. See tanishqkumar.com for background, github.com/tanishqkumar for projects.

EDUCATION

- Westminster School, London, United Kingdom (Sep 2017-June 2019)
 - 11 A* at GCSE, 4 A* at A-Level (mathematics, physics, chemistry, biology)
 - Admitted to study physics (natural sciences) at Trinity College, Cambridge.
 - Coursework: Harvard's CS50: Intro to CS, CS50 Web Programming, Logic/Set Theory, Data Structures & Algorithms, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations.
- AB Physics, Computer Science, Harvard College (Aug 2020-June 2024)
 - Admitted to the Class of 2023, deferred admission to Class of 2024.

RECENT PROJECTS

- RealTalk: Real-time messaging web app with authentication, threads and chatrooms built using Flask-SocketIO & Bootstrap CDN. Functionally similar to Slack.
- BookReads: Social network for rating books and sharing opinions on them. Made using Flask, jQuery, with a mySQL database. Scrapes GoodReads API for data.

WORK EXPERIENCE

• Freelance Software Engineer: ORLibrary (Nov 2019-current)

A vascular surgeon in Abu Dhabi hired me to help build a social network for physicians. Deployment scheduled for January.

Web app allows uploading of operative videos, recommends relevant literature, and matches surgeons via a tiered system to exchange advice/give feedback.

React front-end, Flask back-end, mySQL database, algorithmic matching.

• Freelance Software Engineer: University of Oxford (Oct 2019-current)

Building Artale, a web app for the University's Art Society. Showcases artwork from students at the university, allows purchases, makes recommendations.

HTML5/CSS/JavaScript (with jQuery, Bootstrap, SASS) front-end, Django back-end, PostgresQL database. Deployment scheduled for January.

Hits Stripe API (transactions), Google Cloud API (recommendations), & more.

• Founder, Executive Director: CareerFear (Dec 2015-current)

CareerFear is an education equity nonprofit that works with underserved high schools that lack careers/HE departments for their students. See <u>careerfear.org</u>.

Built a team of 126 volunteers in 14+ branches around the world. Worked directly with 6,000+ students, and impacted 40,000+ more.

Founded at age 14, featured on CNN, Gulf News, Business Matters, amongst others. Won international entrepreneurship awards/scholarships for this work.